The workbook scenario called for having a
person enter two numbers and then return a
random calculation for addition, subtraction,
or multiplication on the two numbers, using
a specific format for the statements returned.
Here is the code example I did to satisfy
the need for the scenario: knowing I would
need random numbers, the code on line 1 imports
the random library.
Lines 2 and 3 use inputs, converted to integers,
to store two numbers in two variables.
Then, on line 5, a function is defined using
the two numbers inputted as arguments.
On line 6, I use the randint method to get
a random number between 1 and 3.
Then, on lines 7 through 15, we have an if
statement that checks the number and adds
the numbers if the random number is 1, subtracts
the numbers if the random number is 2, and,
if the number is 3, as indicated with the
else on line 13, the two numbers are multiplied.
Regarding the print statements on lines 9,
12, and 15, I used the comma to do all the
concatenation so that I do not need to worry
about spacing.
You can also use an f-string format or string.format
on these print statements to get the same
effect.
Lastly, I call the calculate function on line
17.
I will run this code a few times, and we see
the calculations and the statements that we
want.
Again, there is more than one way to write
the code necessary for this project.
As we bring this course to a close, I recommend
getting plenty of practice with the topics
we covered in this course.
Get plenty of practice looking at existing
code and analyzing code to figure out what
the code will do, as we have done many times
in this course.
Make code examples relate to something related
to you, as we have for gaming examples in
this course.
Finally, take advantage of the practice tests
and extra practice opportunities we have provided
in this course.
Thanks again for taking this course, and best
of luck to you in your future endeavors.